Edwin Moz

Software Developer

Cell: 615-336-2315

Email: edwin.moz@outlook.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwin-moz/

GitHub: https://github.com/smileycrew

About Me

Before becoming a software developer, I was a supervisor at a grocery warehouse distributor. My passion for optimizing our operations through technology led to my interest in coding, particularly in creating functions in Google Sheets to enhance efficiency for my colleagues.

Motivated by this passion and the desire to enhance my skills I joined NSS. Now as a junior developer, I stand at the intersection between experience and knowledge, ready to contribute and innovate solutions.

Technical Skills

JavaScript | React | HTML | CSS | Tailwind | C# | .NET | ERDs | Wireframes / Figma | Dependency Graphs / CDGs | Git / GitHub | User Stories | SQLite | PostgreSQL | JSON server | RESTful APIs | Postman |

Projects

Education Connect

Front-end capstone that is designed to serve as an invaluable tool for parents engaged in homeschooling. This platform empowers parents to efficiently manage their homeschooled child's academic journey by offering comprehensive features that cover work tracking, homework assignments, project management, attendance monitoring, and collaborative learning. https://github.com/smileycrew/capstone-project

Education

- Nashville Software School
 Web Development Bootcamp
- Nashville State Community College
 1 year of automotive engineering

Technical Experience

Nashville Software School

Intensive, full-time software development bootcamp focusing on full stack development fundamentals and problem solving. The final half of the program executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology.

- Hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects reflecting real world business problems
- Source code version control and project management with Git/GitHub
- JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Built browser-based single page applications using React, HTML, and CSS
- Styled application with CSS Frameworks, Bootstrap, and Materialize, and wrote custom styles as needed
- Application design through white boarding dependencies and building ERD's
- Created and modified database design / content using SQL, ADO.NET, and ORM tooling, including exposure and experience with migrations
- Created RESTful APIs with C# / .NET using WebAPI

Professional Experience

Associated Wholesale Grocers

Full-time • 12 years 11 months

Grocery warehouse wholesaler to independently owned supermarkets.

Operations Supervisor II

Sep 2018 - July 2023 • 4 years 11 months

- Led the perishable outbound department, overseeing a team of selectors, forklift operators, loaders, sanitation crew, entry-level supervisors
- Managed production and safety standards with precision, enduring consistency, high-quality results
- Collaborated with my supervision team, optimizing time management and implementing streamlined methods to achieve daily operational excellence

Professional Experience Cont.

Operations Supervisor I

September 2015 - September 2018 • 3 years 1 month

- Effectively supervised a team of outbound loaders, ensuring precise loading of trucks while consistently meeting the company's stringent safety and production standards
- Demonstrated strong leadership by spearheading various project and providing guidance and support to fellow supervisors as needed

Warehouse Selector / Forklift Operator

September 2010 - September 2015 • 5 years 1 month

- Proficiently operated heavy warehouse equipment, enduring strict adherence to company production standards
- Demonstrated strong skills and attention to detail in executing warehouse operations efficiently and safely